VIDHYALAKSHMI N

Contact No: 9840881221

Career Objective

Looking forward to enhance my 4 years of developing skill sets in a reputed organization which will clearly help me in improving my career growth and useful in setting up the stronger foundation in my technical arena as well as for the betterment of my family.

Educational Qualification

• Completed B.SC (Computer Science) at Queen Mary's College of Arts and Science, in Chennai with 73% (2016-2019).

Email address: lakshmivl001@gmail.com

- 12th (2015 2016) from St.Joseph Higher Secondary School, Chennai with 82.5% aggregate.
- 10th (2013 2014) from St.Joseph Higher Secondary School, Chennai with 83.4% aggregate.

Work Experience

- ♦ Hexaware Technologies Chennai (Feb 2020 to Dec 2022)
- ❖ VPearl Solutions Chennai (Aug 2023 to present)

Technical skill sets

- Python (Django and Flask Framework)
- Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning (AI & ML)
- Java (Springboot)
- OpenAI and Google cloud translate
- AWS EC2, S3, Lambda
- GCP cloud, Kafka, Microservices(docker)
- SQL(Postgre sql)
- HTML and Javascript
- Prompt Engineering

Roles and Responsibilities

- Worked on few "Translation" Projects for developing a web application using Python as a developing language with HTML and Javascript front end platforms.
- ❖ Integrated on OpenAI models and Google cloud translate model with Django framework to accomplish few application performance.
- ❖ Developed a translation platform using LLAMA model(NLP model).
- ❖ Extensively used Java for backend development(springboot), focusing on building robust, scalable, and secure application. Java was utilized for developing core application logic, handling database interactions, and managing server-side processes.
- ❖ Implemented Apache Kafka for stream processing and managing real-time data pipelines in

various projects. This involved setting up Kafka brokers, designing topics for data streams, and ensuring reliable data transmission and processing across distributed systems.

- ❖ Used AWS cloud services for Deployment such as EC2, Lambda etc.
- ❖ Designed and implemented microservices architectures in various projects, focusing on decoupling services to improve scalability, flexibility, and maintainability.
- Also explored about the National Language Tool Kit (NLTK) package for word tokenizing and extracting the words from the file.
- Generated a few test scripts using some Open AI models and compared the results with the manual testing features.
- Designed an enquiry Chatbot using Googles' Vertex AI and trained the Chatbot using the prompting techniques.
- ❖ Created a instance in google cloud platform(GCP) for deployment of application.
- ❖ Worked on a few front-end projects using HTML and Javascript.
- ♦ Data Analytical skills using SQL(Postgresql, Mysql).

Personal Details

❖ Father's Name : Natarajan. S

♦ Mother's Name : Thangam. N

♦ DOB : 24-04-1999

♦ Gender : Female

♦ Nationality : Indian

♦ Blood Group : O+

♦ Address : 4/985,4th street, Rajendra Nagar

Neelankarai, Chennai-600115

❖ Languages Known : Tamil, English

Declaration

I hereby declare that all the information given above is true to the best of my knowledge and I assure you I will discharge my duties well and clear for the benefit of an Organization and for the betterment of me and my family.

Date: 01/07/2024 Signature

Place: Chennai (N. VIDHYALAKSHMI)